Guide to the Howard Gillette Papers, 1826-2018 MS0644.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Howard Gillette papers
1987-2018
1826-2018
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Gillette, Howard, Jr.,, 1942 -
MS0644.UA
35.5 Linear Feet
Papers of Howard Gillette, Jr., professor of American Studies at both George Washington Univeristy and Rutgers University, including correspondence, memos, fellowship applications, women's studies files, exams, publications, awards, interviews, research notes, and curriculum requirements. They range in date from 1826-2018 with the bulk falling from the mid 1980s through 2018.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the University Archives in three accessions; 1997, 1999 and 2018 September (accession 2018.034)
Historical or Biographical Note
Howard Frank Gillette, Jr. (1942- ) recently retired as Professor Emeritus of History at Rutgers University-Camden. He was a Professor of History at Rutgers University from 1999-2011. Prior to working at Rugter University, Professor Gillette was a Professor of American Civilization and History at The George Washington University from 1970-1999. He was instrumental in helping develop and grow the American Studies Program in his time at GW. Prior to working at GW, Professor Gillette taught at the University of Pennsylvania as a lecturer in American Civilization from 1960-1970. He received his B.A. (1964) and Ph.D. (1970) degrees in American Studies from Yale University.
Professor Gillette is author of "Class Divide: Yale '64 and the Conflicted Legacy of the Sixities (Cornell University Press, 2015); "Civitas by Design: Building Better Communities from the Garden City to the New Urbanism" (University of Pennsylvania Press, 2010); "Camden After the Fall: Decline and Renewal in a Post-Industrial City" (University of Pennsylvania Press, 2005);"Between Justice and Beauty: Race, Planning, and the Failure of Urban Policy in Washington, D.C." (Johns Hopkins University Press, 1995) Professor Gillette was a co-author with Fredric Miller of "Washington Seen: A Photographic History, 1875-1965," also published by Johns Hopkins in 1995. He is editor of "Southern City, National Ambition: The Growth of Early Washington," published by George Washington University in association with the American Institute of Architects in 1995 in conjunction with an exhibit of the same name. He is co-editor of the "Encyclopedia of Greater Philadelphia" (2009-); "The Divided Metropolis" with Willam Cutler (Greenwood Press, 1980); and "American Urbanism" with Zane Miller (Greenwood Press, 1987). His essays have appeared in a wide range of journals, including The Journal of the American Planning Association, the Journal of Urban History, American Quarterly, The Public Historian, Chicago History, Washington History, and Social Science History.
Professor Gillette was the co-director (2001-2010) of the Mid-Atlantic Regional Center for the Humanities, a Rutgers-Temple University partnership, formed in 1999, and currently working with a NEH challenge grant to establish its endowment. He also serves as a faculty associate of the Walter Rand Institute for Public Affairs at Rutgers. Professor Gillette has lectured widely in the United States and abroad. He was a founder and first director of George Washington's Center for Washington Area Studies. He served as editor of Washington History, published by the Historical Society of Washington, D.C. from 1992-1994, and he is immediate past president of the Society for American City and Regional Planning History. He serves on the editorial board of The Journal of Planning History and he has served as exhibits editor for The Public Historian. He has consulted with a number of cultural organizations in the Mid-Atlantic region, including the D.C. Public Library, the Atwater-Kent Museum, The City Museum of Washington, the New-York Historical Society, and the University of Baltimore.
He is a member of the Historical Society of Washington, D.C., Society for American City and Regional Planning History, Urban History Association, National Council on Public History, Historical Society of Pennsylvania Immigration, and Ethnic History Society.
Professor Gillette received the following awards: the Robert W. Kenny Prize for Innovation in Introductory Teaching, 1997; the Class of 1962 Presidential Service Award, Rutgers University, 2006; the Citation of Merit, New Jersey Historical Commission, November 2006; and the President's Award, South Jersey Walt Whitman Preservation Forum, May 2006. "Camden after the Fall" was awarded the following: Best Book North American Urban History, Urban History Association, 2006; the Richard P. McCormick Prize for Best Book in New Jersey History, 2005-2006; Honor Book, New Jersey Council for the Humanities, 2006; and Best Book, 2006, New Jersey Studies Academic Alliance Award.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include correspondence, memos, fellowship applications, women's studies files, exams, publications, awards, interviews, notes, publications and research for publications, and curriculum requirements. These materials were created by Dr. Gillette during his time at GW and at Rutgers University. These materials are related to his research, teaching, and university administrative work. The records range in date from 1826-2018 with the bulk of the materials covering the mid-1980s through 2018.
Collection Organization
Organized into six series: Papers; DC culture, government, suburbs, community life and city programs; Correspondence, letters and notes; Scholarly papers and publications, class materials and projects; Civitas by Design; Class Divide: Yale '64 and the Conflicted Legacy of the Sixties.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Related Materials
Dr Gillette donated two additional collections to GW Special Collections. These related to his work in the GW American Studies Department.
Howard Gillette Collection on the Italian American Community of Washington, D.C. (MS2072) is a collection of materials from the exhibit "Washington's Italian Community 1890-Present" developed and sponsored by the Washington Area Studies Department that was held in November 1984. The collection consists of a significant number of photographs collected from the exhibit, negatives of all materials collected, obituaries, news articles, research notes, correspondence, and other clippings, and copies of the exhibit flyer and the article Alan Kraut and Howard Gillette did for the "Journal of American Ethnic History.https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/246
Howard Gillette Metropolitan Washington Region Urban History subject files (MS2060) The collection includes materials on the history of the greater Washington, D.C. metropolitan area. The collection documents the history of DC communities, focusing on community structure, organizations, politics, events, transportation and difficulties, such as crime and includes paper articles, brochures, pamphlets and letters. https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/238
Women's studies; American civilization; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University. American Studies Dept.; George Washington University; Historical Society of Washington, D.C.; American Institute of Architects; George Washington University. Center for Washington Area Studies
- Papers, 1921-2017; Series 1
  Arrangement
  This series follows the materials' original order.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a variety of materials, including memos, correspondence, oral histories, fellowship applications, and various George Washington University class curricula, discussions, and exams. The materials range in date from 1921 to 2017.
  - Memos, 1987 -1988; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Oral History, Undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Women's Studies, Undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Public Historian, Undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Memos, 1993 -1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990 -1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memos, 1994 -1995; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AHA [American Historical Association], Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Urban History Discussion, 1996; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Urban History Syllabi, 1981-1996; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Urban History Exams, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Urban History Discussion, 1998; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Social History Discussion, Spring Semester, 1996; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1997 -1998; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1996 -1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Memos, 1996 -1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Information, Ethnology Advising Com, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Undergraduate Self-Study, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Undergraduate Curriculum, 1996 -1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Undergraduate Curriculum, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - American Cities & Suburbs, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Public Historian, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - [American Civilization] 71, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Grade Sheets, 1976; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Am Civ [American Civilization] 71, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - [American Civilization?] 72, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Am Civ [American Civilization] 225, DC History, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1996; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Memos, 1995-1996; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fellowship Applications, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - American Urbanism [1/2], Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - American Urbanism [2/2], Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - U.S. Social History, Undated; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Sprawl, 1996-2001; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Gruen, Victor, 1950-1992; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Shopping Centers, 1978-2003; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Reframing the 1945-1965 Suburb, 1999; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Suburbs, 1987-2016; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Moses, Robert, 1973-2007; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Urban Renewal, 1953-1993; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Highways, 1979-2017; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - New Towns, 1971-1998; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Bartholomew, Harland, 1943-1998; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Housing, 1975-2004; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Housing Acts (1949 and 1954), 1949-1954; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 1939 World's Fair, 1979-1998; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Pruitt-Igoe, 2011-2016; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Public Housing Documents, 1921-1950; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Public Housing, 1992-2016; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Bauer, Catherine, 1934-1937; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - New Deal, Housing, 1998; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Fishman, Metropolis Unbound: The New City of the 20th Century, 1988-1989; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Addams, Jane, 1991-2002; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Cooley, Charles Horton, 1968; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Garden Cities, 1996-2007; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Chicago Plan (1909), 1926-1994; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Olmstead, Frederick Law Jr., 1991; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Robinson, Charles Mulford, Undated; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - City Beautiful, 1903-1981; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Progressivism, 1910-1989; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - 1893 World's Fair, 1983-1992; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Frederick Law Olmstead, 1991; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Suburban, 19th Century, 1978-1987; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Urban Parks, 1974-2011; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Lowell, Massachusetts, 1976-1992; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Mill Towns, 1969-1998; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Urban History Syllabi, 2017; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 35)
- DC culture, government, suburbs, community life and city programs, 1845-2013; Series 2
  This series contains a variety of materials related to Washington, D.C.'s culture, government, city programs, community life, and suburbs. Materials include newspaper clippings, magazine articles, notes, and memos. The materials range in date from 1845 to 2013.
  - National Cathedral, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Old Executive Office Building, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pentagon, 1986-1992; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Tudor Place, 1988-1991; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Union Station, 1988-2000; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The White House, 1992-10; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Barney, Alice Pike, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Baroni, Geno, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Glenn, Brown, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Josephine Butler, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cassell, Albert, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Edgartown Mass, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - David Clarke, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Diggs, Charles, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Douglas, Frederick, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Drew, Charles, 1994; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Ellington, Duke, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Force, Peter, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Gichner, Henry, 1994-1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Grant, Ulysses S. III, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Green, Constance, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Horsky, Charles, 1997-08-24; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Jesse Jackson, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - L'Enfant, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Liebow, Elliot, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Meigs, Montgomery, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - McShain, John, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Miller, Herb, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Moore, Arthur Cotton, 1980-1986; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Nolen, John Jr., 1986-06-27; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Shepard, Alexander, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Mitch Snyder, 1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Stallings, George, 1997; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Tibbs, Thurlow, 1984-1997; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Toomer, Jean, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Wardman, Harry, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Whitman, Walt, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Barry '98 paper, 1990-2000; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - NCHA, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - NCPC 2000 Plan, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Abbott Prohibition, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - DC Obits, 1983-1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - DC Press, 1972-1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - DC Photographers, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - DC Public Works, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - DC Public Buildings, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Neighbors Inc, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Parks - DC, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Pennsylvania Ave. Devt. Corp., 1996; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Playgrounds, 1901-1920; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Police, 1990-1991; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Port America, 1995-1997; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Poverty, 1988-1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Prisons, 1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Prostitution, 1999; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Real Estate, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Real Estate Ads - DC, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Redevelopment, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Religion/Activism, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Rhodes Tavern, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Rivers, 1983; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Schools, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Shopping Centers, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Southern Migration to DC, 1987; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Suburban Sanitary Commission, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Transportation: Beltway, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Transportation: Metro, 1995-1998; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - DC Trans: Whitehurst Freeway, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - DC Transportation: Highway, 1997; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Tourism, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Trans: Parkways, 1981; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Welfare, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - W. Writers, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Zoning, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Accokeek Foundation, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Associates for Renewal in Ed., Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Corcoran, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Greater Washington Research Center, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - D.C. Preservation League, 1996; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Humanities Council, DC, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Latin American Youth Center, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - RAP: Drug Program, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - School Without Walls, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - United Planning Organization, 1967; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Washington/Rolt - Association, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Metro Wash Planning & Housing Assn, 1950-1964; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Washington Project for the Arts, 1988; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - The Past in the Future: Prepared for the Washington Center for the Metropolitan Studies by Frederick Gutheim, 1968; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Oxford: Washington, D.C., Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - American University Washington College of Law Program on Law and Government and American University Law Review, 1998-10-02; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Washington D.C Politics, 1982-1990; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Politics, by Ward, 1987-1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Politics Ward 8, 1992-1993; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Politics Kelly Admin, 1994; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Politics Statehood, 1982-1990; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - A New Columbia: The Case for DC Statehood, Undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Diner Democracy Federalism & the Governance of the Nation's Capital, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Rimensynder, Nelson Local Govt. in DC, 1801-71, 1977; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Clinton/DC, 1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - DC Control Board, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Control Board: Schools, 1996-1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Carol O'Cleireacain The Orphaned Capital, 1996-1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Economic Development, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Fuller Economy of DC, 1996-1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Dc Tax Cuts, 1994-1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - DC Appleseed Center, 1995-11; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Democracy First, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - DC Democracy Initiative, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Committee for the Capital City, 1999; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Nat. Assn. to Restore Pride in America's Capital, 1997-03; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Task Force on DC Governance, 1996; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Court Challenge, 1998; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Adams v. Clinton, Undated; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Dc Agenda, 1993-1999; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - DC Council Evaluation, 1999-02; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - University Seminar on DC, 1996; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - A transformed Government for the People of Washington, D.C., 1996-02; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Political Flyer, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Advisory Neighborhoods Commissions, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Aids, 1991-1994; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Apartment Houses, 1993-1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Arena, 1971-1995; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Architects, 1984-1998; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - DC Art, 1978-1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Auto - DC, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - DC Black History, 1972-1986; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - African American Interview, 1996-1997; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Black Church, 1981-1992; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Black Catholics, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - African American Lawyers, 1986; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Black Migration, 1987; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Black: Obits, 1979-1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trade, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Business, 1978-1986; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Business Relocation, 1993; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - DC Business Trade Association, 1982-1984; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Business Public Relations, 1986; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Capitol, 1993; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Chesapeake Bay, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Cemeteries, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - C & O Canal, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Churches, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Churches, Catholics, 1994; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Interfaith Network, 1995; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Churches: United House of Prayer, 1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Churches: Union Baptist, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - City Planning, 1975; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Committee of 100, 1978-1995; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Convention Center, 1994-1997; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Dorothea Browder Day Care Centers in DC, 1996-01-30; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Decatur House, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Department Stores, 1993-1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - D.C. Defense, 1992-1994; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - D.C. Village, 1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Developers - DC, 1981-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - District Building, 1995; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Enterprise Zones, 1989-1994; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Funeral Homes, 1994; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Asians, 1985-1987; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Cambodians, 1995-02-19; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Ethnics, DC, Cubans, 1987-1989; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Czech Community DC, 1979-08-16; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Ethiopians, 1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Ethnics: Germans, 1894; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - DC; Ethnicity: Greeks, 1985-04-27; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Ethnicity: Italians, 1994-03-25; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Italian Interviews, 1984-1988; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Jews, 1983-1997; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Koreans, 1992-1995; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Latinos, 1986-1995; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - DC: Vietnamese, 1985-1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Fed/City Relations, 1989-1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Federal City Council, 1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Federal Payment to DC, 1991; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Federal Triangle, 1998; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Film, 1989; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Food, 1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Forest Glen, 1982-1989; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Friendship House, 1994; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Foundations: DC, 1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Gay Community, 1997; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Gentrification, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - GWU History, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Health Care, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Skyline/Height Limits, DC, 1987-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - High Tech, 1998-06-10; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Highways, 1937; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Homelessness, DC, 1986-1999; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - DC Housing, 1982-1997; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Housing Alley Life, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Public Housing, 1993-1998; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Housing: Benning Terrace, 1997; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Housing: Clifton Terrace, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Housing: Ellen Wilson Homes, 1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Housing Mail Order Homes, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Housing: Mayfair Mansion, 1991-09-19; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Housing: Paradise Manor, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Housing Rent Control, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Housing Valley Green, 1992; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Howard University, 1997; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Langston Terrace, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 83)